

Bogdan Alexandrescu

Bogdan is a technology expert and industry leader. A successful entrepreneur with previous start-ups in technology, fintech, and business consulting. Member of the Bitcoin Foundation and active investor and advisor in the blockchain ecosystem. Tech Lead at Apple Inc, with a focus on large-scale Machine Learning & Al infrastructure projects. Previously Tech Lead for Twitter Ads

bogdan@alexandrescu.io http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandrescu

(415) 660-8886 San Francisco, CA

Experience

Apple (Cupertino, CA)

Tech Lead Sr. SWE, MAPS, June 2017 - Present



Architect, build and support Big Data, Machine Learning and Al pipelines at scale for the
real-time analysis of Apple MAPS data and services. Lead an org-wide standardization and
integration effort meant to streamline and improve the ongoing evaluation of MAPS data
and service releases.

Senior SRE, MAPS, March 2016 - June 2017

 Build and support distributed and highly available compute platforms. Productionalize and automate big data ingestion and processing pipelines. Software product arhitecture reviews and disaster recovery strategies, tooling and monitoring. Agile sprint planning and training.

Twitter (San Francisco, CA)



Software Engineer - Tech Lead, Ads, Jun 2015 - Dec 2015

 Design and implement client facing features and advertising formats for twitter.com in order to drive up engagements and increase overall product quality and advertising revenue. Coordinating tasks and syncronizing with other leads, PMs and designers on technical requirements, UX/UI designs & release dates as well as supporting and mentoring teammates.

Software Engineer, IO, April 2014 - May 2015

• Lead the design and development of an end-to-end capacity planning and management solution. Other projects involved building reliable and highly available automation software in distributed environments (Mesos, Hadoop) to handle an end-to-end strategy for fleet analytics, provisioning, allocation and infrastructure operations.

UC Davis (Davis, CA)



Research - Assistant Specialist, Jan 2012 - Jan 2016

Develop and maintain a MySQL database driven Web Applications and UC Davis AWS
 Server for collecting and administrating the research data needed for the Federal Grant
 (USDA) funded projects.

AV Franchise Consulting (Bucharest, RO)



Founder & CTO, April 2009 - August 2011

• Lead the technology efforts of one of the biggest franchise consulting businesses in Romania. Provided integration (website, In house CRM software) for the company's database of 6000 clients/partners management. Built the web directory with the highest traffic in this business segment in Romania.

Webstyle Solutions (Bucharest, RO)



Founder & Team Lead, April 2007 - August 2011

• Provided leadership, architectural, and process direction for the following services and products: web development, web hosting, domain registry, IT outsourcing and website

maintenance. Lead the efforts in the integration of electronic payment systems with Authorize.net, PayPal, Mobilpay and Gecad.



Bogdan Alexandrescu

Bogdan is a technology expert and industry leader. A successful entrepreneur with previous start-ups in technology, fintech, and business consulting. Member of the Bitcoin Foundation and active investor and advisor in the blockchain ecosystem. Tech Lead at Apple Inc, with a focus on large-scale Machine Learning & Al infrastructure projects. Previously Tech Lead for Twitter Ads

bogdan@alexandrescu.io http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandrescu

(415) 660-8886 San Francisco, CA

Education

Harvard Business School

HBX CORe, 2016-2017

Graduated with Honors

University of California, Davis

MS, Computer Science, Sep 2012 - April 2014

GPA: 3.85/4.0

Cibernetics, Statistics & CS - ASE Bucharest

BS, Computer Science, Sep 2004 - June 2008

GPA: 3.65/4.0

Skills

- Software Engineering: Golang, Python, Scala, Java, Solidity, PHP, Bash/Shell, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Flight.js, AngularJS, ReactJS, Typescript, Jasmine, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle), Non-SQL (MongoDB, Redis, Manhattan, Elastic Search, Solr, Cassandra), Distributed Computing (Mesos/Maraton/Aurora, Kubernetes, Hadoop/HDFS, Spark, Heroku, AWS Stack, Zookeeper), Blockchain Technology, Jenkins, Artifactory, Druid/Superset, Tableau, Kibana
- System Engineering: Docker, VMWare, Citrix Netscaler, Nginx+, HAProxy, DNS, Kickstart, Verdad, Switch and Network configuration, Firewalls, Puppet, Chef, Tracing, Splunk, ELK Stack, Zipkin, Zabbix, InfluxDB/Grafana
- Information Security: Intrusion Detection, PEN Testing, Cryptography
- **Leadership**: Serial entrepreneur and advisor. Leading teams of engineers working on software and large scale infrastructure projects
- **Project Management**: Scrum and Agile Metodology project management
- Languages: Fluent speaker of English, Italian, Romanian and beginner level in French, Spanish & Mandarin.

Leadership Affiliations

- Bitcoin Foundation, Active Member (2018 Present)
- Blockchain Investors Consortium, Active Member (2017 Present)
- Graduate Student Association, UC DAVIS, Computer Science Representative (2012-2013)
- Mensa, Active Member (2011 Present)
- Rotaract (Rotary International), President 2012 (2008 2012)
- Business Club & VIPRomania, Active Member (2004-2008)





